{"tossups": [{"question": "This politician wrote the<em> My Day</em> column to advocate for civil rights and helped create a planned community in Arthurdale to provide homes for disenfranchised miners. This probable lover of Lorena Hickok employed social secretary Lucy Mercer, who indirectly inspired this woman to broaden her social life by having an affair with her husband. The UN Commission on Human Rights was chaired by, for ten points, what American social reformer, the wife of the 32nd President?", "answer": "(Anna)<b> E</b>leanor<b> Roosevelt</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Spanish Moors who performed this action were called<em> moriscos</em>. For ten points, name this action that was performed by Henry IV upon winning the French Wars of Religion, supposedly declaring \u201cParis is well worth a Mass.\u201d", "answer": "<b> converting to Catholicism</b> (accept word forms and equivalents; prompt on \u201cconverting religions\u201d and similar; only prompt on \u201cconverting to Christianity\u201d after \u201cMoors\u201d has been read)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "During this conflict, a leader\u2019s plans were almost derailed by a charge led by Baldwin de Carron and Garnier de Nablus. Forces captured the Sultanate of Rum\u2019s capital during this conflict\u2019s Battle of Iconium. Prior to this campaign, Guy of Lusignan was captured at the Battle of Hattin. After the Battle of Arsuf in this crusade, an invasion failed to take Jerusalem. Christians were allowed access to holy places in Jerusalem as a result of, for ten points, what crusade against Saladin led by Richard the Lionheart?", "answer": "<b> Third Crusade</b> (\u201dCrusade\u201d not needed after mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this type of incident in which Aaron Burr shot and killed Alexander Hamilton.", "answer": "<b> duel</b>s Page 2", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During a voyage from Madagascar, the pirate John Thurber gave Henry Woodward this crop, which Woodward turned into a major crop in North America. The Engelberg Huller and Winnowing Barns processed this crop. Thomas Jefferson investigated why an Italian variety of this crop was more expensive than the \u201cCarolina Gold\u201d variety, which was grown near the Ashley and Combahee Rivers in tidal zones. The Banaue [ban-ow-ay] terraces in the Philippines were created to grow, for ten points, what food crop?", "answer": "<b> rice</b> Page 3", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 2005, this man was dismissed as Deputy President after his friend, Schabir Shaik, was convicted on fraud and corruption charges. This former communist recently faced impeachment after the case<em> Economic</em> <em>Freedom Fighters v. Speaker of the National Assembly</em> ruled that he had siphoned funds meant to upgrade the Nkandla house. During this man\u2019s 2005 rape trial, he claimed that he took a shower to prevent himself from contracting HIV. Improper ties to the Gupta family helped bring down, for ten points, what former President of South Africa?", "answer": "Jacob<b> Zuma</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "Salmon P. Chase served six years in the Senate as a member of this political party. As a senator from New Hampshire, a presidential candidate of this party led the drive to abolish flogging in the Navy. This party, whose final presidential nominee was John P. Hale, emerged when the Barnburners withdrew their support from Lewis Cass, instead nominating Martin Van Buren for the presidency. For ten points, name this anti-slavery party tht was active from 1848 until its absorption by the Republican Party.", "answer": "<b> Free Soil</b> Party", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This city\u2019s two largest soccer clubs, Everton and a club whose anthem is \u201cYou\u2019ll Never Walk Alone,\u201d play the Merseyside Derby. Anfield is the home of \u201cthe Reds\u201d in, for ten points, what English industrial port city, the home city of the Beatles?", "answer": "<b> Liverpool</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "This man allegedly dismembered Marcus Marius Gratidianus and paraded his head around the streets of Rome. Gaius Cethegus and Lentulus Sura were accomplices to this man in his most famous action, which was chronicled by Sallust. This man used the promise of cancellation of debts to recruit veterans to his cause, which grew out of resentment toward his loss of the 64 BC consular election. Four orations were made against this man by Cicero, this man\u2019s rival and target. For ten points, name this Roman who led a failed conspiracy against the Roman Republic.", "answer": "<b> Catiline</b> (or Lucius Sergius<b> Catilina</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "After it was invaded by Batu Khan, this empire was put under the so-called \u201cTatar Yoke.\u201d A grand prince who ruled this empire employed the Varangians to reconquer Novgorod in 978. Figures like Yaroslav the Wise ruled, for ten points, what ancient Russian federation of the Middle Ages, based in modern Ukraine?", "answer": "Kievan<b> Rus</b>\u2019 (prompt on Kiev)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man sent Crist\u00b4obal de Olid to conquer Honduras, but later sent two warships after him when he declared independence. After landing at Veracruz, this man scuttled his own ships to prevent his men from retreating. This man had a son with his interpreter, La Malinche, who was one of the first mestizos. This man\u2019s only surviving documents, the Cartas de Relaci\u00b4on, describe how he was mistaken for a feathered serpent god. For ten points, name this Spanish conquistador who conquered the Aztec empire.", "answer": "Hern\u00b4an<b> Cort\u00b4es</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This politician advocated for an end to apartheid in the \u201cDay of Affirmation\u201d Speech, and he wrote about his experiences serving as chief counsel for the McClellan Committee and feuding with Teamsters boss Jimmy Hoffa in his book<em> The Enemy Within</em>. Shortly after a meeting with Cesar Chavez, this man announced his campaign to run for President, but after winning the 1968 California primary, he was assassinated. For ten points, name this politician who served as Attorney General under his brother, John.", "answer": "<b> R</b>obert Francis<b> Kennedy</b> (accept<b> RFK</b>; accept<b> Bobby Kennedy</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A documentary of \u201cscorched earth techniques in China\u201d inspired the first movement of a piece that this composer dubbed his \u201cwar symphony.\u201d This composer, whose<em> Symphony in Three Movements</em> was choreographed by George Balanchine, wrote the latter half of his neoclassical<em> Symphony in C</em> after fleeing Paris in 1939. This man wrote a ballet in which Kaschei the Immortal is defeated when Prince Ivan destroys a magic egg. For ten points, name this Russian-born modernist composer of<em> The Firebird</em> who caused a Parisian riot with<em> The Rite of Spring</em>.", "answer": "Igor<b> Stravinsky</b> BONUS:<em> The Firebird</em> was the first of Stravinsky\u2019s collaborations with what impresario, who founded the Ballets Russes [\u201cballet\u201d roose] and also produced<em> The Rite of Spring</em>? ANSWER: Sergei<b> Diaghilev</b> <b></b> (1) <b>In response to a rebellion led by the Senussi Order, this man ordered the genocidal</b> <b>\u201cpacification\u201d of another country. In a confrontation with Greece, this leader sent troops</b> <b>to bombard and occupy the island of (+)</b> <b>Corfu. This leader formed the one-time Stresa</b> <b>Front with his counterparts, Pierre Laval and Ramsay MacDonald; the Front broke apart after this man declared war against (*)</b> Haile Selassie [\u201chighly\u201d sel-ah-see]. This man rose to power when a march by his Blackshirt paramilitaries forced the hand of Victor Emmanuel III. For ten points, name this fascist Italian dictator. ANSWER: Benito Amilcare Andrea<b> Mussolini</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Dance"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this member of the Mercury Seven, the first American astronaut to orbit the Earth.", "answer": "<b> ammonia</b> (accept<b> NH</b><u>3</u> before mentioned; do not accept ammonium) (3) <b>This man piloted the</b><em><b> MiG Mad Marine</b></em><b>. In the Savings and Loans scandal, this man</b> <b>and John McCain were the only members of the Keating Five to be acquitted. The first</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>panorama photo of the United States was taken in an aircraft piloted by this man.</b> <b>This senator from Ohio flew in the</b><em><b> Discovery</b></em><b> in 1998, becoming the (*)</b> oldest man in space. As pilot of the<em> Friendship Seven</em>, this man made three orbits of Earth in 1962. For ten points, name this member of the Mercury Seven, the first American astronaut to orbit the Earth. ANSWER: John<b> Glenn</b>", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "<b>A relief by Pietro Lombardo showing a man reading at a lectern is found in one of these locations that is controversially in Ravenna instead of in Florence. Petrarch planted a tree</b> <b>at one of these locations in the entrance to a (+)</b> <b>tunnel in Naples. A glass wall was built</b> <b>around one of these locations designed by Jacob Epstein to curtail the tradition of visitors putting on lipstick and kissing a stone sculpture of a sphinx. (*)</b> Poet\u2019s Corner of Westminster Abbey is home to several of, for ten points, what historic sites that sometimes do not actually contain the remains of people like Dante, Virgil, or Oscar Wilde?", "answer": "<b> tomb</b>s of authors (accept equivalents related to<b> burial site</b>s,<b> grave</b>s, etc. of authors; accept Dante\u2019s<b> Tomb</b>, Virgil\u2019s<b> Tomb</b> starting at the second sentence, or Oscar Wilde\u2019s<b> Tomb</b> starting at the third sentence) Page 10", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>Louis Menand\u2019s \u201cThe Metaphysical Club\u201d discusses the birth of this intellectual school from a conversational club founded by Oliver Wendell Holmes Jr. The namesake \u201cmaxim\u201d of this school argues that the conception of an idea is only made up of its (+) effects. Charles Sanders Peirce is known as the \u201cfather\u201d of this school, whose most famous proponent argued for it as a (*)</b> \u201cNew Name for Some Old Ways of Thinking.\u201d For ten points, name this American school of philosophy that focused on the practical consequences of ideas.", "answer": "<b> pragmatism</b> (accept word forms)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The third wave of these items were marketed with a poster showing the caption \u201cOver the top for you.\u201d Mary Pickford started a nationwide speaking campaign to sell these items,</b> <b>which were advertised by a division of the (+)</b> <b>Creel Committee. During the drive to sell</b> <b>Creel Committee. During the drive to sell</b> <b>the fifth wave of these, medallions representing them were created by the (*)</b> <b>the fifth wave of these, medallions representing them were created by the (*)</b> Treasury Department using metal melted from German cannons. Over $17 billion dollars were raised by the sale of, for ten points, what loans used to fund the Allies during World War I?", "answer": "<b> liberty bond</b>s (accept<b> liberty loan</b>s; accept<b> Victory Loan</b>s; accept<b> war bond</b>s) Page 11", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>The \u201cAlbion Hall Group\u201d organized a strike in this city that culminated in Bloody Thursday. Harry Bridges led a 1934 Longshoreman\u2019s strike in this city. Mayor Eugene</b> <b>Schmitz declared (+)</b> <b>martial law in this city after looting in 1906. A 1915 World\u2019s</b> <b>Fair celebrated the rise of this city \u201cfrom the ashes\u201d following an (*)</b> earthquake on the San Andreas Fault. The 1849 Gold Rush helped the growth of, for ten points, what city where the Golden Gate Bridge opened in 1937?", "answer": "<b> San Francisco </b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}